자막제작 - NSC 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/tsm)
- 여기가 확실해요?
- 확실해요
- You sure this is it?
- This is it.
몇 시예요?
What time is it?
3시 20분요
3:20.
- 안 보이는데요
- 여기 있을 거예요
- I don't see him.
- He'll be here.
몽크 씨, 정말 그 남자가 트루디에 대한
정보를 가지고 있다고 생각해요? / 네
Mr. Monk, do you think he really
has information about Trudy? / Mm hmm.
단지 보상금을 받으려고
거짓말하는 거라면요?
What if he's lying just
to get the reward money?
거짓말하는 게 아니라면요?
진짜라면요?
What if he's not?
What if he's the real thing?
제가 돈을 가지고 있어도 될까요?
Can I have the cash?
돈을 줘요 / 괜히 희망에 부풀지
않으셨으면 하는 것뿐이에요
Give me the cash. / I just don't want
you getting your hopes up.
나탈리, 난 그다지 큰 희망을
걸고 있지 않거든요
Natalie, I don't have
an abundance of hope.
그나마 가진 작은 희망이라도
만끽하게 해 줘요. 돈 주시겠어요?
Let me enjoy the little I have.
Please, give it to me.
알았어요
Okay.
좋아요. 당신은 저기
화장실 옆에서 기다려요
Okay, you wait over there
by the facility thing.
뭐라고요? 변소 말이에요?
What, you mean the bathroom?
- 화장실이라고 부르는 걸로 아는데요
- 혼자 두고 갈 순 없어요
- I believe they're called facility things.
- I'm not leaving you.
나탈리, 그 남자가 혼자 오랬거든요
당신이 있는 걸 보면 가 버릴 거예요
Natalie, he said to come alone.
If he sees you here, he won't stop.
몽크 씨, 제 일은 당신을 돕는 거예요
Mr. Monk, my job is to help you.
화장실에서 당신을
기다리는 게 아니라고요
Not to wait for you in the facility thing.
트루디에 관련된 일이니
내가 꼭 해야 해요. 부탁이에요
This is about Trudy.
I've got to do this, please.
좋아요
All right.
하지만 확실하지 않으면 남자한테
지불하지 않겠다고 약속하세요
But just promise me you won't
pay him unless you're sure.
도움이 필요하면
소리를 질러 불러 줘요
If you need anything, yell.
행운을 빌게요
Good luck.
이봐요
Psst.
이봐
당신이 몽크요?
You Monk?
- 나 줄 돈이오?
- 사진을 갖고 있다고 말했죠
- They're for me?
- You said you had a picture.
손가락이 여섯인 남자를 찾고 있었죠?
You've been looking for
a six fingered man?
그래요
Yeah.
어디서 이걸 찍었나요?
Where did you get this?
내가 직접 찍었죠
Took it myself.
캐나다 밴쿠버에서 만났소
그 남잔 취해 있었지
I met him in Bancouver, Canada.
He was drunk.
당신 부인을 자동차 폭발로
죽였다고 떠벌리더군요
He was talking about killing
your wife with a car bomb.
그 남자 이름은 뭡니까?
What's his name?
사진은 공짜지만, 몽크 씨
The picture's free, Mr. Monk.
이름을 알려면
대가를 지불해야 할 거요
The name's gonna cost you.
자, 잠시만요
W, wait, wait a minute.
- 이 여섯 번째 손가락이...
- 그래요. 뭐가 어때서요?
- This sixth finger.
- Yeah, what about it?
손마디에 털이 없어요
No hair on the knuckle.
이 사진은 조작된 거예요
차량 번호판도 캐나다 것이 아니고
This photograph has been doctored
and the license plate is not Canadian.
도움 될 정보를 전혀
갖고 있지 않군요. 그렇죠?
You can't help me at all, can you?
돈 이리 내놔
Give me the money.
나탈리
Natalie.
나탈리!
Natalie!
빌어먹을
Damn it.
몽크 씨
Mr. Monk.
MONK Season 4 Epi. 11
Mr. Monk Bumps His Head
토니 샬롭
(에이드리안 몽크 役)
트레일러 하워드
(나탈리 티거 役)
제이슨 그레이 스탠포드
(랜달 디셔 경위 役)
테드 리바인
(리랜드 스토틀마이어 경감 役)
딕테이션
진현경(jhk8012@nate.com)
싱크편집
윤선영(seedyun@nate.com)
한글번역
박도현(oreocookie@nate.com)
번역수정
한상희(fithelestre@sanori.net)
홍관호(kwanho_hong@nate.com)
번역수정
한글교정
임재영(dreamimage@nate.com)
ORIGINAL AIR DATE ON USA: 2006/01/20
이봐요
Hey.
무슨 짓이오?
What are you doing?
이 뒤에 타면 안 돼요
You can't ride back here.
이게 그레이하운드 버스인 줄 아슈?
(장거리 시외버스 회사 이름)
Does this look like
a greyhound bus to you?
아뇨. 버스는 창문이랑 좌석이 있죠
No, buses have windows and seats.
어이, 말하자면 그렇다는 거지
Hey, it was a rhetorical question.
괜찮아요?
Are you all right?
이봐요, 형씨
나야 태워 주고 싶지만
Look, buddy, it's not me.
이 뒤에 사람이 타다 걸리면
보험을 잃게 될 수도 있어서 그래
But if I get caught with a civilian
back here, I could lose my insurance.
저기, 돈은 있수?
Listen.
Do you have any money?
- 아뇨. 미안합니다
- 잠깐, 잠깐만요
- No, I'm sorry.
- Wait, wait, wait.
여기요
요기나 좀 하슈
Here.
Buy yourself some dinner.
뭐 하는 거요?
What are you doing?
주름을 펴고 있는데요
Smoothing it out.
왜요?
Why?
나도 모르겠어요
I don't know.
안녕, 커비
Good afternoon, Kirby.
코라
Cora.
- 이따가 비가 올지도 모른다더라
- 아, 곧 알게 되겠지
- They said it might rain later.
- Oh, well, we'll know soon enough.
징시한테 줄 음식을 좀 샀어
녀석이 제일 좋아하는 상표야
I got some food for Jinxy.
That's his favorite brand.
내가 없는 동안 보호소에서
완전히 다른 상표를 먹였더라고
They fed him a completely different
brand at the shelter while I was gone.
어디 갔다 왔어?
You were gone?
그래. 휴가 좀 갔다 왔지
막 돌아왔어
Yeah, I was on vacation.
I just got back.
좋았겠네
주말 동안 바람도 쐬고
Good for you.
A little a weekend getaway.
사실은 석 달 동안 갔다 왔어
Actually I was gone for 3 months.
유람선을 탔거든. 기억나?
너한테도 얘기했었는데
I was on that cruise, you remember.
We talked about that.
나한테 사진 많이 찍으라고
했잖아 / 내가 그랬나?
You told me I should take
a lot of pictures. / Did I?
목요일에 사진이 나올 거래
빨리 보여 주고 싶다
They'll be ready on Thursday.
Can't wait to show you.
특히 그리스. 난 거기에 그렇게
많은 섬이 있는지 몰랐거든
Especially Greece. I never knew
there were so many islands.
미안, 코라
Excuse me, Cora.
미안해. 막 안쪽 방을 청소하러...
Sorry, I just remembered that
I have to go pick up..
- 가야 한다는 게 기억났어
- 그래, 알았어
- clean up the back room.
- Oh, okay.
괜찮아
Okay.
- 사진 나오면 또 들를게
- 그래, 그래. 그렇게 해
- I'll bring those pictures around.
- Yeah, yeah, you do that.
좋아
All right.
이봐요, 당신
Hey, excuse me.
이봐요
Hey.
이봐요. 내 애마한테
지분덕거리지 말아요
Hey, don't ponce my ride.
뭐 하는 거요?
What are you doing?
그게... 약간 맞지 않네요
It's just...
it's not quite straight.
"애마한테 지분덕거리지 말라"는
말 중 어디가 안 맞는다는 거요?
What part of "Don't ponce my ride"
don't you understand?
지분덕...
Ponce...
대부분...
실은 전부 못 알아듣겠어요
Most of... all of it really.
이봐. 이건 BMW 5 시리즈라고
알겠어?
Look, man, this is
a BMW 5 series, all right?
우리 마누라한테도
손끝 하나 못 대게 하는 차야
I don't let my wife touch this car.
마누라가 사 줬는데도 말이지
And she bought me this car.
그런데 댁이 함부로 손대게
내버려 둘 것 같아?
You think I'm gonna let you
touch it?
이 양반아, 왜 이래?
Buddy, what is your problem?
모르겠어요
멈... 멈출 수가 없네요
I don't know.
I can't... I can't stop.
내가 왜 이러는지 몰라도
거의 다 됐어요. 이것만...
I don't know what's wrong with me,
but it's almost there, just this...
당신한테 바람구멍을
하나 새로 뚫어 주면 어떨까?
Hey, how about I just
rip you a new one?
아뇨, 아닙니다
Uh, no.
No, no.
새 구멍은 필요 없어요
I don't need a new one.
당신 어디서 굴러 왔어?
Where you from?
모르겠어요 / 그럼 마을을
위해 부탁 하나 하지
I don't know. / Well, how about
you do this town a favor.
어디서 왔는지 생각해 내서
얼른 거기로 꺼지시지
You figure out where it is you're from
and get your sorry ass back there.
알겠어요
Okay.
고마워요
Thank you.
그거 윌리 넬슨이야?
(컨트리 가수. 에피소드 1x12 참조)
Is that Willie Nelson?
너 컨트리 음악 싫어하잖아
You hate country music.
너 이번 주 내내 입에서
노래가 끊이질 않는구나
You've been coming in singing
and dancing every day this week.
그 남자 이름이 뭔데?
What's his name?
그냥 기분이 좋은 것일 수도 있지
난 뭐 그러면 안 되니?
Well, maybe I'm just happy.
Isn't that possible?
물론 되고말고
Sure, it's possible.
그 남자 이름이 뭐냐니까?
What's his name?
어머, 어서 오세요
Oh.
Good morning.
- 저 좀 먹여 주실래요?
- 시도해 보죠
- Can you feed me?
- We can try.
아침, 점심, 아니면 저녁요?
Breakfast, lunch, or dinner?
상관없어요
어차피 같은 메뉴니까요
Um. / Doesn't matter.
It's the same menu anyway.
원하시는 데 아무 데나
앉으시면 돼요
Well, you can sit anythere you like.
Oh.
여기요
Here.
바로 여긴 어떠세요?
How about right over here?
세상이 지나가는 걸 볼 수 있죠
You can watch the world go by.
Ha.
지나가지 않는 것도 볼 수 있고요
Or not go by.
주문하세요
Here we go.
선생님?
Sir?
손님?
Excuse me.
괜찮으세요?
Are you okay?
싸우거나 뭐 그러셨어요?
Did you get in a fight or something?
Uh.
마실 것 좀 갖다 드릴까요?
Can I get you something to drink?
물 있나요?
Do you have any bottle of water?
- 갖다 드리죠
- 잠시만요
- We could do that.
- Wait.
좋아하는 상표가 있거든요
I have a favorite brand.
전 그 상표만 마셔요
It's the only brand I drink.
그게 이름이...
It's called...
이름이...
It's called..
기억이 안 나네요
Oh, I can't remember.
그냥 있는 것 갖다 드릴게요
I'll just bring you ours.
저 사람들한테 얘기해서
직원 명단을 얻어 내게
Talk to those guys.
Get a list of their regulars.
어젯밤 여기 주차한 트럭 운전사들
명단도 전부 확보하고
I want a list of all the truckers
that park here over the night.
제 잘못이에요. 몽크 씨 곁을
떠나지 말았어야 하는 건데
This is my fault.
I should never have left him.
그럼 "아뇨, 나탈리 잘못 아녜요
자책하지 마세요"라고 하셔야죠
You're supposed to say, no, Natalie,
it's not your fault, stop blaming yourself.
미안해요
Sorry.
그렇게 말해 줘요!
Say it.
나탈리 잘못 아녜요
자책하지 마세요
It's not your fault,
stop blaming yourself.
- 모두 내 잘못이에요
- 경감님!
- It's all my fault.
- Captain.
- 뭘 찾았나?
- 지갑을 찾았어요
- What have you got?
- Found his wallet.
신분증은 들어 있는데
돈이 없어졌어요
ID's still in there, money's gone.
강도라... 믿거나 말거나
좋은 소식이군
Robbery. Well, believe it or not,
that's good news.
왜요? / 유괴범의 소행이었다면
지갑을 털지는 않았을 테니까요
Why? / If it was a kidnapper,
he'd have other things on his mind.
경감님, 몽크 씨가 돈을 모두
은행에서 출금했거든요
Captain. Mr. Monk gets all his money
from the bank.
새 지폐들이었으니까, 어쩌면
일련번호를 추적할 수 있을 거예요
They're brand new bills.
Maybe they keep track of serial numbers.
그거 좋네요
우리가 확인하죠
That's good.
We'll check it out.
혹시 이 남자가 정말로 트루디의
죽음에 대해 정보를 가지고 있었고
Maybe this guy really did have
a clue about Trudy's murder
몽크 씨가 그 사건을
해결한 건 아닐까요?
and Monk solved the case.
몽크 씨가 트루디의 살해범을
찾아서 죽였다는 뜻입니다
I mean, he found the guy
who killed Trudy and killed him.
그러고는 어디 다른 장소로 가서
이름을 바꾸고 새 인생을 시작한 거예요
And then he moved to some place else,
changed his name and started a new life.
- 우리한테 말도 안 하고?
- 늘 있는 일인걸요
- Without telling us?
- Happens all the time.
- 늘 있다고?
- 때때로 있는 일이죠
- It does?
- It happens occasionally.
전에 없던 일도 아니잖아요
It's not unprecedented.
못 들은 걸로 하세요
I never said it.
좋아
Good.
어떠셨어요?
How was everything?
물은 어땠어요?
How's that water?
좋은데요
I like it.
그것 보세요. 좋아하는 상표가 새로
생기셨잖아요. 아주 뜻 깊은 날이네요
See, you have a new favorite brand.
It's a big day for you.
그래요
Yeah.
그냥 궁금해서 그러는데요
Now, I'm just curious.
왜 음식마다 전부 다른 접시에
놓아두세요?
Why do you have everything
on different plates?
- 종교적인 이유 같은 게 있어요?
- 그럴 거예요
- Is that like a religious thing?
- I guess so.
그래서 2분마다
손을 닦으시는 거예요?
Is that why you wash your hands
every two minutes?
아마도요
Probably.
각자 취향이 다르니까요
To each his own.
여기 있어요
준비되시면 언제든지
Here we go.
Whenever you are ready.
- 이런, 12달러 50센트
- 문제가 있나요?
- Oh, 12,50.
- Is there a problem?
5달러밖에 없어요
I only have 5 dollars.
사정이 많이 안 좋으신가 보군요
You're having a rough time, aren't you?
저기요, 나머지는 제가 낼게요
형편이 풀리면 갚으세요
You know what, I'll pay the rest.
Pay me back when you can.
데비, 무슨 짓이야?
Debby.
What are you doing?
난 이분이 정직한
사람이란 걸 알 수 있어
I can tell he's an honest guy.
제가요? / 네
I am? / Mm hmm.
당신 말이 맞는 것 같아요
I think you're right.
난 정직해요
I am.
고마워요
나중에 갚을게요
Thank you.
I will pay you back.
- 약속해요
- 서두를 것 없어요
- I promise.
- There's no rush.
우린 둘 다 죽을 때까지
여기 있을 테니까요 / 네
- We're both gonna die here.
- Yeah.
아, 죄송하지만
Oh, excuse me.
경찰 본부는 어디쯤 있나요?
How far am I from police headquarters?
본부요?
Headquarters?
실례합니다
Excuse me.
규정을 어긴 걸 들켰구먼
You caught me cheating.
- 아무한테도 말하지 마세요
- 그럴게요
- Don't tell anybody.
- I won't.
뭘 도와 드릴까요?
What can we do for you?
- 약간 혼란스러워서요
- 아, 늘 있는 일이죠
- I'm a little confused.
- Oh, that happens all the time.
어디 보자... 고속도로에서 빠져나와
주유소를 찾고 있었군요
Let me guess, you got off Interstate
and you were looking for a gas station.
아뇨, 아뇨...
길을 잃은 게 아닙니다
No, no, no.
I'm not lost.
전...
Well, I am.
제가 누군지 모르겠어요
I don't know who I am.
기억을 못한다고요?
기억 상실증처럼?
You can't remember,
like amnesia?
앉아요
Have a seat.
거기 주먹만 한 혹이 났네요
It's a hell of a speed bump
you got there.
어디 얼음주머니가 있을 겁니다
I've got an icepack somewhere.
- 의사한테 혹을 보여 봤소?
- 모르겠어요
- Has a doctor seen that?
- I don't know.
- 어쩌다 그렇게 됐소?
- 그건 제가 말씀드릴게요
- How'd that happen?
- I'll tell you how it happened.
코라? / 페인트 통이 머리에 떨어져서
배 밖으로 떨어질 뻔했거든요
Cora? / A paint can dropped on his head
and he about fell overboard.
배 밖으로요?
Overboard?
그걸 어떻게 알죠, 코라?
How do you know this, Cora?
제가 거기 있었으니까요
이탈리아 나폴리였어요
Because I was there.
It was in Naples, Italy.
- 나랑 같이 유람선에 탔었죠
- 그럼 이 남자를 알아요?
- He was on my cruise.
- So you know this man?
네, 알아요
알다 뿐이겠어요
Yeah, I know the man.
Of course I know the man.
이이는 제 남편이에요
He's my husband.
좀 나아?
Feel better?
그래야 할걸
15시간이나 잤다고
You should.
You slept for 15 hours.
이상한 꿈을 꿨어요
I had the strangest dream.
당신이 금발인 꿈을 꿨어요
I, I dreamt that you were a blonde.
금발?
A blonde?
그리고... 그리고 꽤
And, and you looked pretty.
다르게 생겼어요
정말 다르게 생겼더라고요
Different.
Pretty different.
- 뭐 해?
- 글쎄요
- What are you doing?
- Well, I'm..
그냥 종교적인 행동이에요
It's just a religious thing.
음식 갖고 장난치지 말고
그냥 먹어
Don't play with your food.
Just eat it.
알겠어요
Okay.
지붕이 또 그러네
The roof again.
이 거지 같은 집구석!
This place is a dump.
예, 유감이네요
Yeah, I'm sorry.
우리한테 고양이가 있네요
We have a cat.
- 당신은 고양이를 사랑하잖아
- 난 고양이를 사랑하는군요
- You love cats.
- I love cats.
징시, 여긴 내 새 남편인 제리야
Jinxy, it's my new husband Jerry.
- 제 이름이 제리예요?
- 제리 리틀이지
- My name is Jerry?
- Jerry Little.
내가 제일 좋아하는 이름인
제레미아를 줄인 거야
Short for Jeremiah,
which is my favorite name.
- 그거 정말 우연의 일치네요
- 그래?
- That's certainly a coincidence.
- Isn't it?
이 옷들은 새 건가요?
Oh, are these clothes new?
내가 어제 사 준 거잖아
보기 좋은데
I bought them yesterday.
They look good.
당신한테 잘 어울려
Ooh, that is a good look on you.
다... 다른 옷들은 어디 있죠?
Where, where are my clothes?
당신이 잃었잖아
몽땅 날렸어
You lost them.
You lost everything.
도박으로
Gambling.
내가 도박을 하는군요
I gamble. / Mm hmm.
자기는 심각한 도박 중독이야
Darling, you have a serious addiction.
멈추지를 못하지
Can't stop yourself.
여행 가방째로 몽땅
붉은 쪽에 걸었잖아
(룰렛 게임을 말함)
Bet all your luggage and
bet everything you own on red.
나도 그 카지노에 있었어
I was in the casino.
내가 당신을 보고 있었지
거기가 우리가 만난 곳이야
I was watching ya.
That's where we met.
- 이번엔 또 왜?
- 우유...
- Now what?
- The milk.
무... 무서워요
I feel frightenend.
- 우유가 무섭다고?
- 어떻게 그럴 수 있죠?
- You're afraid of milk?
- How is that possible?
내가 왜 이러는 거죠?
What, what is wrong with me?
아마 머리를 부딪혔을 때
문제가 생겼을 거야
It probably happened when
you banged your head.
며칠만 있어 봐
괜찮아질 거야
Just give it a few days.
You'll be okay.
병원에 가 보는 게 좋겠어요
Maybe I should see a doctor.
병원에 갔었잖아
기억 안 나? / 아, 맞다
Oh, you saw a doctor.
Don't you remember? / Oh, right.
의사가 당신보고
날 믿으랬어. 그리고...
He told you to trust me and
내가 시키는 대로 따르라고
to do everything that I say.
알겠어요, 여보
Yes, dear.
Oh, oh.
돈이 좀 필요할 것 같아요
식당 점원한테 7달러를 빌렸거든요
I'm gonna need some money.
I owe that waitress 7 dollars.
- 그런 걸 뭐 하러 신경 써?
- 그냥 옳은 일을 하고 싶어요
- What do you care?
- I just wanna do that right thing.
나중에 처리해
지금 당장은 집안일 좀 봐 줘
Maybe later.
Right now, you got some chores to do.
당신은 집안일 하는 걸 좋아해
You love doing chores. / Oh.
여기 목록이 있어
Here's your list.
지붕을 고치라고요?
아뇨, 아뇨. 난 못해요
Fix the roof?
No. No, I can't.
물론 할 수 있어
당신은 지붕 수리공이잖아
Sure you can.
You're a roofer.
- 내가 지붕 수리공이라고요?
- 그게 당신 직업이야
- I'm a roofer?
- That's your job.
이렇게 하지, 용감한 여보
지붕을 고쳐 주면 이따가 밤에
I tell you what, tiger.
You fix the roof and later on tonight,
내가 얼마나 많이
고마워하는지 보여 줄게
show you how much I appreciate it.
여기 당신 연장통이야
얼른 올라가
Here's your toolbox.
Off you go.
이번엔 또 왜?
Now what?
난... 무서워요
I'm..
I'm afraid.
2단이나 올라갔잖아, 제리
당신은 할 수 있어
you're up two feet, Jerry.
You can do this.
지붕 수리공이 된 이유도
고소 공포증을 극복하기 위해서야
That's why you became a roofer,
to get over your fear of heights.
효과도 있었잖아
당신은 세계적인 유명인이야
And it worked.
You're world famous.
제리, 당신은 모든 지붕 수리공의
왕이야. 자, 올라가
Jerry, you're the king of all the roofers.
Now up you go.
그럴게요, 여보
Yes, dear.
내가 지붕 수리공이야?
I'm a roofer?
대체 무슨?
What the hell?
도와줘요!
Help.
살려 줘요!
사람 살려! 누가 벌 좀 떼어 줘요!
Help. Somebody get them off me.
- 이 남자 알아보겠어요?
- 아뇨
- You recognize him?
- No.
저 남자 이름은 테디 멀리건이에요
His name is Teddy Mulligan.
몽크의 돈에 관해서는
당신이 옳았어요
You were right about Monk's money.
일련번호로 멀리건을 찾았죠
모든 걸 자백했어요
The serial numbers led us right to him.
He's confessed to everything.
몽크를 속여서
보상금을 빼앗으려 했대요
He tried to con Monk
out of the reward money.
그럼 몽크 씨는 어디 있어요?
Then where's Mr. Monk?
- 멀리건이 싸움이 있었다고 말하더군요
- 오, 세상에
- Mulligan says there was a fight.
- Oh my god.
- 그리고 멀리건이 몽크의 머리를 쳤대요
- 어쩜 좋아
- And Mulligan hit him on the head.
- Oh my god.
그리고 몽크를 트럭 뒤에 내던졌는데
트럭이 떠나 버렸답니다
And he threw him on the back
of a truck and the truck drove away.
자기는 거기까지밖에 모른대요
That's all he knows.
몽크 씨는...
Is he..
몽크 씨는 죽었을까요?
Is he dead?
아닌 것 같습니다
I don't think so.
시체를 발견했단 보고가 없었어요
There's been no report of a body.
이봐요
Hey.
몽크는 분명 저 밖에 있어요
He's out there.
누군가가 몽크를 봤다면
우리가 찾을 겁니다
If somebody's seen him,
we'll find him.
약속해요
I promise.
어서 오세요. 또 오셨네요
Hey, welcome back.
- 안녕하세요
- 잘 지냈어요?
- Good afternoon.
- Hey.
- 두 분이 함께세요?
- 네. 우린 결혼했거든요
- Are you two together?
- Yeah, we're married.
우린 결혼했죠
이쪽은 제 남편 제리예요
We're married.
This is my husband Jerry.
제 이름은 제리입니다
My name is Jerry.
그리고 우린 결혼했죠
And we're married.
정말요?
No kidding, well.
- 축하드려요
- 감사합니다
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
예. 영화의 한 장면처럼
제가 탔던 유람선에서 만났어요
Yeah, just like in the movies.
We met on that cruise I took.
카지노에서 눈이 마주치자
꽝!
Saw each other in the casino
and boom.
우린 알았어요
첫눈에 반한 사랑이란 걸 말이죠
We knew it, didn't we?
We knew. Love at first sight. / Oh.
그렇게 된 거죠
That's how it happened.
분명히
Evidently.
데비 있어요?
돈 갚을 게 있거든요
Is Debby here?
I owe her some money.
없어요
오늘 아침에 그만뒀어요
No.
She quit this morning.
- 그만뒀다고요?
- 말 그대로요
- She quit?
- Just like that.
이 편지를 문에서 발견했어요
Found this note on the door.
남자 친구가 덴버로 가는데
같이 따라간대요
Said that her boyfriend's moving
to Denver and she's going with him
언제 돌아올지는 자기도 모르고요
and she doesn't know
when she'll be back.
내가 제일 친한 친구였는데
나한테는 한마디도 안 했어요
I was her best friend.
She didn't say a word to me.
여기 뭔가 이상한 게 있어요
There's something wrong with this.
봐요
번진 걸 봐요
Look.
Look at that smudge.
이 편지는 왼손잡이가 썼는데
This note was written by
a left handed person,
데비는 오른손잡이였죠
but Debby is right handed.
- 맞아요, 그래요
- 데비가 쓴 게 아닌 것 같아요
- That's right, she is.
- I don't think Debby wrote this note.
데비가 어디 살죠?
Where does she live?
바로 옆집요
저한테 열쇠가 있어요
Right next door.
I have the key.
당신이 왜 그 여자를 걱정해?
What do you care about this girl?
난 그냥 확인하고 싶은 거예요, 여보
I just wanna check it out, dear.
그럼 빨리해. 왜냐면...
Well, make it fast, cuz
집안일 할 것도 있고
사랑도 나눠야 하니까
I get home and I got chores to do
and loving to make.
데비가 돌아와서 우릴 보면 어쩌지?
그 생각은 한 거야?
What if she comes back and finds us?
You ever think about that?
뭐 해?
What are you doing?
생각하고 있다고 생각해요
I think I'm thinking.
그게 생각하는 방법이야?
That's what you think?
둘러보고 싶으면
보통 사람들처럼 둘러봐
If you want to look around,
look around like a normal person.
창피하게스리
난 이 동네에서 살아야 한다고
You're embarrassing me.
I gotta live in this town.
미안해요, 여보
I'm sorry, dear.
여긴 뭔가 이상해요
Something is wrong here.
데비는 이 새를 어릴 적부터
키웠던 것 같아요
It looks like she's had this bird
her whole life.
그냥 두고 갈 리가 없는데
안 그래요?
She wouldn't just leave it behind,
would she?
이런 걸 어떻게 알아채는 거야?
How are you noticing this stuff?
나도 몰라요
I don't know.
그냥 그런 게 보이니까
I'm just seeing things.
솔직히 말해도 돼?
Can I be honest with you?
난 당신이 지붕 고치는 일에
지금처럼 집중했으면 좋겠어
I wish you would concentrate like this
on your roofing work.
그럴게요, 사랑하는 여보
Yes, my beloved.
임신 테스트로군요
Pregnancy test.
- 임신했나 보네
- 어떻게 알아요?
- Looks like she had a bun in the oven.
- How do you know?
거기 작은 선이 둘 있잖아
임신했다는 뜻이거든
Those two little lines there,
that means positive.
봐...
그 끝에다 오줌을 누고...
See, you pee on that end.
물티슈
Wipe.
물티슈, 물티슈
Wipe, wipe.
- 물티슈 좀, 물티슈가 필요해요
- 알았으니까
Wipe. Give me..
I need a wipe. / All right.
진정해
Relax.
Ugh.
깨진 유리네
Broken glass.
깨진 유리...
이 탁자는 옮겨졌어요
This table has been moved.
누군가 몸싸움을 한 것 같아요
I think somebody was fighting in here.
이 테이프 보여요?
Do you see this tape?
바로 여기 깔개가 있었어요
There was a rug right here.
아직 끈적거리네
Still sticky.
자, 왜 데비가 자기 옷은
모두 남겨 두고 떠나면서
Okay, why would she leave
all of her clothes behind,
깔개는 가져갔죠?
but take the rug?
코라
Cora.
난 이 불쌍한 여자가
살해당했다고 생각해요
I think this poor girl
has been murdered.
보안관님, 안전한 거 확실해요?
Sheriff, are you sure it's safe?
전 벌이 싫거든요
I hate bees.
벌은 걱정 말게나
Don't worry about the bees.
레리랑 네드가 다 몰아갔어
벌들은 금방 잠잠해진대
Larry and Ned's got them all rounded up.
They're fast asleep.
그랬으면 좋겠다는 거지
I hope.
보안관님, 그 여종업원에 대해
어떻게 생각하세요?
Sheriff, what do you think?
About the waitress.
글쎄, 내 생각엔...
어떻게 생각하느냐고?
Well, I think..
What do I think?
난 데비가 남자 친구랑
덴버로 갔다고 생각해요
I think she went to Denver
to be with her boyfriend.
- 내가 뭐랬어?
- 아뇨, 아뇨, 보안관님
- I told you.
- No, no, no. Sheriff.
보안관님
잉꼬가 있잖아요
Sheriff.
What about the parakeet?
없어진 깔개도 있고요
그리고 보세요
And the missing rug..
And look..
보세요, 여기...
편지는 어쩌고요?
Look, wait.
What about the note?
전 이 편지를 데비가 썼다고
생각하지 않거든요. 보이세요?
I don't think she wrote
this note herself. See that?
- 보안관님
- 이름이...
- Sheriff.
- Mr...
미안합니다. 당신 이름을 잊었소
I'm sorry, I forgot your name.
- 저도 그래요
- 제리
- So have I.
- Jerry.
제리요 / 제리, 사건이란
TV에 나오는 것과는 달라요
Jerry. / Jerry, it's not like
it is on TV.
실제 상황에서 사건들은
보이는 것 거의 그대로죠
In real life, things are
pretty much the way they seem.
예를 들면, 이건 음주 운전
사고처럼 보여요. 그렇죠?
For example, this looks
like a drunk driving accident, right?
그럼 실제로도
음주 운전 사고라 이겁니다
That's exactly what it is.
운... 운전수가 취했었나요?
He... he was drunk?
아, 그럼. 곤드레만드레 취했지
Oh, yeah, drunk as a skunk.
오늘 아침 8시, 이 동네
바람둥이 로저 지스크가
8 o'clock this morning
Roger Zisk, local hotshot
저 울타리를 부수고 벌들한테
돌진해서 100여 방을 쏘였어요
plough through that fence into these
bees and got stung about 100 times.
- 멍청이
- 자요, 보안관님
- Idiot.
- Okay, Sheriff.
피해 목록입니다
Here's my list.
그 녀석이 개당 400불짜리
제 벌집 5개를 덮쳤어요
He knocked over 5 of my honeycombs,
worth 400 a piece.
거기다 울타리 6미터도요
피해액은 누가 보상하죠?
Plus 20 feet of my fence.
Who's gonna pay for all that?
로저가 보험에 들었을 걸세, 네드
I'm sure he's insured, Ned.
당연히 그래야죠
말썽꾸러기 녀석!
He'd better be.
That boy's a brat.
주정뱅이 망나니 같으니
그 녀석은 늘 그랬어요
A drunken spoiled brat.
He always has been.
쏘여서 팅팅 부었으니
고소해 죽겠어요 / 네드...
- I'm glad he got stung and swollen.
- Ned, uh...
저 위 조망대 근처에 있는
말벌 집 좀 어떻게 처리해 주게나
Why don't you head up to lookout point
and see what you can do about
those hornet's nest.
애들이 매일 거기에서 쏘인다네
We got kids getting
stung up there everyday.
갈 거예요. 갑니다
I'm going, I'm going.
하지만 그 날건달 놈한테
꼭 배상하라고 하세요
But that punk owes me money.
- 창문이 올라가 있어요
- 그래서?
- The windows are up.
- So what?
왜 차 안에서 머물지 않았을까요?
밖엔 온통 벌들이 있었는데요
Why didn't he stay in the car?
He was surrounded by bees.
- 저라면 그냥 안에 있었을걸요
- 구시렁 구시렁 구시렁
- I would've just stayed put.
- Yackety-yak yak.
무슨 말을 하는 거야?
What are you talking about?
아마 놀라서 그랬겠죠
아까 말했듯이 엄청 취해 있었거든
He probably panicked.
Like I said, he was really wasted.
제 생각은 좀 다릅니다
I don't think so.
8시 직전쯤에 그 사람을 봤는데
I saw him.
Just a few minutes before 8,
우리 집 바로 옆으로
차를 몰고 지나갔거든요
he drove right past our house.
길에 나뭇가지가 있었는데
그걸 피하려고 차를 돌렸어요
There was a branch in the road.
He swerved to avoid it.
로저의 반사 작용은 완벽했어요
His reflexes were perfect.
취해 있었을 리가 없어요
He couldn't have been drunk.
취해 있었어요
He was drunk.
고의로 꿀벌 농장으로
차를 몰았다고?
He deliberately drove his car
into this bee farm.
- 대체 누가 그런 짓을 하겠어요?
- 저도 모르겠어요
- Why would anybody do that?
- I don't know.
그리고 데비 바넷이 덴버에 간 것이
아니라 살해당한 거라고요?
And Debbie Barnet isn't in Denver,
she's been murdered.
혹을 의사에게 보여 봤나요?
Have you seen a doctor about
that bump.
혹 때문이 아니에요
중년의 위기 같은 거죠
It's not the bump.
It's some kind of midlife crisis.
갑자기 지붕을 고치는 게
행복하지 않게 된 거죠
All of a sudden, he's not
happy fixing roofs.
정의의 사도라도 되려나 봐요
대체 뭐가 문제야?
He's gotta be Captain America.
What is wrong with you?
"윌리 넬슨"
몽크는 머리를
심하게 얻어맞았어요
He got beaned pretty hard on the head.
이 전단을 4000장 정도
붙이도록 지시할 겁니다
We're putting up 4000 of these.
I'm gonna have them put up.
어디에 붙이게 됩니까?
Where you're gonna post them?
우체국, 트럭 정거장과
약국에 붙입니다
Post offices, truck stops,
and drug stores.
자, 잠시만요. 왜 약국이죠?
W, wait, why the drug stores?
몽크가 머지않아 물티슈를
사야만 할 거다 싶어서요
I figure he's gonna have to buy
wipes sooner or later.
경감님, 제게 말씀하신 증상의
기억 상실증은 사실 꽤나 드뭅니다
You know, Captain, the amnesia that
you're describing to me is actually quite rare.
그럴 수도 있겠지만
Maybe.
달리 설명할 도리가 없습니다
But it's all we got.
시신도 발견 못했고
몽크에게 연락도 안 왔어요
I have no body.
He hasn't contactd us.
나탈리한테도 연락이 없었고요
He hasn't contacted Natalie.
예. 전국의 모든 병원에 통지했지만
아무런 소식이 없습니다
Yeah, we've notified every hospital
in the country. There's no sign of him.
박사님, 만약 제 말처럼 몽크가 어딘가
살아 있고 자신이 누군지 모른다면
Doctor, if I'm right and Monk is out there
and he doesn't know who he is,
그걸 어떻게 생각해야 하죠?
what can we expect?
심리학적인 관점으로 보자면
정립되지 않은 영역에 있다고 봐야죠
From a psychological stand point,
we'd be on uncharted territory.
몽크는 완전히 의식이
분열된 상태일 겁니다
Adrian would be in a complete
dissociative state.
계기반도 없이 안개 속을 날고 있는
비행기 조종사와 같은 거죠
He would be like a pilot who's
flying in the fog without any instruments.
죽을 만큼 무서움에 떨고 있겠군요
He's gotta be scared to death.
하지만 재미 있는 건
만약 심하게 다치지 않았다면
But in a weird way,
if he's not seriously hurt,
몽크에게 도움이
될 수도 있다는 겁니다
this could actually help him.
에이드리안은 늘 자신을 객관적으로
한 발 떨어져서 바라보지 못하는
You see, Adrian has always
had a problem detaching,
장애를 겪고 있었습니다
looking at himself objectively.
그러니, 만약 경감님 예상이 맞다면
So if you're right,
몽크는 저 어딘가에서 생애 최초로
자기 본모습을 직시할 기회를 가진 거죠
he could be out there right now
meeting himself for the very first time.
몽크가 자기 본모습을 본다고요?
He's meeting himself?
그건 안 좋은데
That can't be good.
어이, 제리
Hey, Jerry.
제리?
Jerry?
이봐요, 제리!
Hey, Jerry!
잠시 얘기 좀 할 수 있소?
Could I talk to you a minute?
오늘 아침 당신이 얘기했던, 로저가
취한 척했다던 말을 생각해 봤어요
I've been thinking about what
you said this morning about
Roger pretending to be drunk.
로저의 차에서 피를 좀 발견했는데
갓 흘린 피가 아니더군요
We found some blood in his car.
It wasn't fresh.
그 전날 밤에 흘린 피였어요
It was from the night before.
충돌 사고가 있기 전에 다쳤군요
He hurt himself before the crash.
- 어딘가 다른 곳에서요
- 그럴 수도 있지
- Some place else.
- Well, could be.
그리고 데비 바넷의 소식을
들은 사람이 아직 아무도 없소
In the meantime nobody's
heard from Debbie Barnett.
정말 두 사건이
연관되었다고 생각해요?
Do you really think there's
a connection?
- 글쎄요... 보안관님 생각은요?
- 음...
- Well, what do you think, Sheriff?
- Hmm.
로저를 만나 보고
진술을 들어 보려 하는데
I'm gonna go over and talk to Roger,
see what he has to say.
- 같이 갈 생각 있소?
- 네
- You want to join me?
- Yeah.
주에서 제일 큰 사료 가게죠
It's the biggest feed store in the county.
로저의 장인 소유인데
Roger's father in law owns it.
로저가 맡아서 운영하고 있어요
He lets Roger run it.
이런 말씀을 드리긴 뭐 하지만
I don't wanna tell you,
저 부대 자루들 냄새가 마치...
but those bags smell like...
부대 자루에 든 게 바로 그거거든
Well, that's exactly what they are.
거름이죠
That's fertilizer.
세상에
Oh, my god.
이럴 수가... 이건 마약 거래보다
더 심한 짓이에요
My god, this is worse than
drug trafficking.
이 남자를 체포하셔야 해요
You gotta nail this guy.
보안관님 / 로저
Sheriff. / Roger.
좀 어떤가?
How are you feeling?
뭐, 괜찮아질 겁니다
I'll, you know, be all right.
사람들은 늘 제 얼굴이 부어 있다는데
(swelled head : '자만하다'라는 뜻)
People always say that
I had a swelled head.
그 말이 결국은 맞은 것 같네요
(swelled head : '자만하다'라는 뜻)
Well, I guess they're finally right.
이 사람은 여기 왜 왔죠?
What's he doing here?
- 둘이 만난 적 있나?
- 네, 만났고말고요
- You two met?
- Yeah, you could say that.
이쪽은 코라의 새 남편인 제리일세
Well, this is Jerry,
Cora's new husband.
제리는 오늘 날 거들고 있다네
- He's been helping me out today.
- Yeah, well.
저기요, 제가 저쪽에 좀
피해를 준 건 압니다
Listen, I mean I know I did
some damage out there.
하지만 네드한테 제가
처리할 거라고 말해 주세요
But just tell Ned
I'm gonna take care of it.
제가 지불할 수 있다는 걸
아시잖아요
You know I'm good for it.
저도 오늘 아침 현장에 있었는데요
I was out there this morning.
타이어 자국을 보면
당신이 멈췄다가...
From the tire tracks, it looked
like you stopped,
뒤로 방향을 틀어서는...
then turned around and then..
꿀벌 농장으로
돌진한 걸로 보이더군요
Then drove into that bee farm.
고의로 그랬단 뜻인가요?
농담하세요?
You mean on purpose.
Are you kidding?
140방이나 벌에 쏘여 봤어요?
Look, you ever been stung
140 times?
- 그건 장난이 아니거든요
- 로저
- Cuz it's no picnic.
- Roger.
자넨 데비 바넷을 알지. 그렇지?
You know a Debbie Barnett, right?
네, 물론이죠
Yeah, sure.
분명히 데비는 아무에게도
말하지 않고 동네를 떠났네
Well, evidently she left town
without telling anybody.
데비의 부모님과 막 얘기했다네
대단히 걱정하시더구먼
I just talked to her parents.
They're mighty worried.
데비와 사귄 적이 있나, 로저?
You haven't been seeing her,
have you, Roger?
보안관님, 전 유부남이라고요
Sheriff Bates, you're talking
to a married man.
- 데비가 임신한 건 알았나요?
- 제가 그걸 어떻게 압니까?
- Did you know she was pregnant?
- Well, how would I know that?
- 윌리 넬슨을 좋아합니까, 로저 씨?
- 네, 좋아해요
- You like Willie Nelson, Mr. Zisk?
- Yeah, he's all right.
- 왼손잡이시죠. 아닙니까?
- 칼, 이 남자 누굽니까?
- You're left handed, isn't that right?
- Carl, who is this guy?
난 할 일이 있어요
이 남자한테 알려 주세요
Look, I got work to do.
Just educate this guy, all right?
제가 누군지
똑똑히 알려 주시라고요
You tell him who he's talking to.
저자가 범인이에요
경감님께 전화합시다
He's the guy.
Let's call the captain.
무슨 경감?
What captain?
저도 모르겠어요
I don't know.
제리
Jerry.
당신 방식이 마음에 드는군요
I like your style.
사실 난 부관을 찾고 있었거든
As a matter of fact,
I've been looking for a deputy?
부관? / 보안관님이 내가
훌륭한 탐정이 될 거래요
A deputy? / Sheriff said I would make
a great detective.
내가 타고났대요
He said I was a natural.
내 보증인이 되어 주고
지원서 쓰는 것도 도와주신대요
He said he would sponsor me,
help me with the application.
- 잊어버려
- 코라
- Well, forget that.
- Cora.
여보
Darling.
보안관님 말씀이 맞는 것 같아요
들어 봐요
I think he's right.
Listen.
사실 난 나 자신이 그다지
마음에 들지 않거든요
The truth is I don't like myself
very much.
온통 이상한 버릇들 투성이고
항상 불안한 느낌만 들고요
I have all these strange habits.
I'm nervous all the time.
하지만 오늘 범죄 현장에
있었을 때는
But when I was there today,
at the scene of the crime,
갑자기 모든 게 이해되더라고요
suddenly it all made sense.
사건들이 내 머릿속에서
이해되었어요. 딸깍 딸깍!
Things were clicking in my head.
Click, click.
난 경찰이랑 같이 못 살아
난 경찰이 싫다고
I'm not living with a cop.
I hate cops.
당신은 지붕 수리공이야
알았어? 대화 끝!
You're a roofer.
Understand? Conversation's over.
- 네, 하지만...
- 꿈은 그만 꾸라고 했지
Yes. / I told you to stop dreaming.
- 그랬어요
- 그럼 여기 앉아 봐
- Yes.
- Now sit down here.
날 믿지. 그렇지?
You trust me, don't you?
사랑해
I love you.
그러면...?
And?
"나도 사랑해요"라고 해야지
You love me, say it.
당신을 사랑해요
I love you.
침실에서 만나
I'll meet you in the bedroom.
얼마나 이걸 기다려 왔는지 몰라
I've been waiting a long time for this.
신혼여행이 있었잖아요?
What about our honeymoon?
아, 맞아. 그걸 잊었네
마치 마법 같아서 말이야
Oh, yeah, I forgot about that.
That was magical.
여기 앉아
Sit down right here.
손 이렇게 올려 봐
And put your hands like this.
이제 숙여
Now, lean in.
트루디, 트루디
Trudy. Trudy.
내 이름은 코라야
My name is Cora.
미안해요
I'm sorry.
뭔가가 기억나요
I'm remembering something..
여자가 있는데...
There's a woman I..
나 아무래도 트루디란 여자랑
바람을 피우고 있나 봐요
I think I'm having an affair
with a woman named Trudy.
용서할게
I forgive you.
네. 난 그 여자를 사랑하는 것 같아요
Yeah, I think I love her.
상관없어
I don't care.
사실은 난 당신에게
그다지 끌리지 않아요
The truth is I'm not so
attracted to you.
- 그러시든지
- 사실은...
- Whatever.
- The truth is...
당신은 좀 무서워요
you sort of terrify me.
야!
Hey.
- 완벽한 결혼 같은 건 없어
- 네
There's no such thing
as a perfect marriage. / Right.
알았어, 그래. 내 잘못이야
내가 좀 재촉했나 봐
All right, look. This is my fault.
There's too much pressure.
밖으로 나가자
자연스럽게 분위기도 잡힐 거야
Let's... let's get out of here.
We'll be spontaneous.
응?
그래, 알아
Huh?
Hey, I know.
우리 조망대로 가자
젊은 애들도 많이 가잖아
Let's go to lookout point.
That's where all the kids go.
오, 안 돼요
Oh, no.
안 돼요, 못 가요
No, we can't.
No.
기억 안 나요?
보안관이 말하길...
Remember, Sheriff said...
거기 꿀벌이랑 말벌들이
많다고 했잖아요
they were having a problem
up there with the bees and the hornets.
사람들이 죄다...
Everybody's getting...
쏘이고 있다고요
Stung.
- 코라
- 침대에 누울까?
- Cora.
- Should I lie down?
내가 막 사건을 해결한 것 같아요
I think I just solved the case.
잘됐네요. 고마워요
Great.
Thank you.
나탈리
Natalie.
나탈리, 이봐요
Natalie, hey.
몽크 씨를 찾았어요
We found him.
몽크 씨는 괜찮대요?
Is he okay?
확신은 못하겠네요
트럭 운전사가 전단지를 봤대요
We're not sure.
Trucker saw one of the fliers,
어제쯤에 와이오밍에서 내려 줬다고
전화로 알려 왔어요
called in, said he dropped him off
in Wyoming sometime yesterday.
와이오밍요?
Wyoming?
프로나우란 이름의 작은 동네래요
아주 외진 곳이죠
It's a little town called Prono.
It's out in the middle of nowhere.
FBI가 제트 비행기를 빌려 준다니까
2시간이면 거기 갈 수 있어요
The FBI's loaning us a jet
and we can be there in 2 hours.
하지만 확실한 거예요?
정말 몽크 씨래요?
But is it sure?
Was it really Mr. Monk?
트럭 운전사가 5달러 지폐를 줬는데
그 남자가 그걸 계속 펴더래요
Trucker gave the guy 5 dollar bill,
and the guy kept smoothing it out.
오, 살아 있군요
Oh, he's alive.
차... 차 안에 벌이 있어요
There's a... there's a bee in the car.
밖에는 약 2만 마리가 있어요
벌들은 낯선 사람을 좋아하지 않죠
Well, there's about 20000 of them out here
and they don't like visitors.
자, 이걸 입어요
Here. Put this on.
여기 있소
사이즈 하나로 다 맞거든
There you go.
One size fits all.
좀 어때요?
How's that feel?
진정해요
그게 제일 중요하지
Try to relax.
That's the most important thing.
꿀벌과 말벌은
두려움의 냄새를 맡거든
Bees and hornets can smell fear.
불안해 하면 할수록
더 달콤한 대상으로 생각하죠
The more nervous you get,
the sweeter you are to them.
자, 입어 봐요
There you go, jump in them.
침착하게... 그래, 그래
괜찮아요. 겁먹지 말고
Easy does it. There, there.
Don't panic.
빨리 움직이지 말아요
팔은 거기에 넣고
Now don't move fast.
Get your arm in there.
좋아요
Good.
알았어요, 알았어
I got it, I got it.
사탕처럼 달콤하구먼
팔을 거기에 넣어요
Sweet as candy.
Put your arm in there.
좋아요
괜찮아요
That's good.
It's all good.
보안관님, 뭔가를 발견했는데요
Sheriff, we got something.
데비를 찾았어요
We found her.
검시관이 오는 중입니다
가엾은 것
County coroner's on his way.
Poor kid.
데비가 어디 있는지는
어떻게 알았어요?
How did you know where she was?
문득 명확하게 떠올랐어요
Just seemed obvious.
문득 떠올랐다고?
Obvious to you.
네
Yeah.
제 생각에는 말이죠...
Here's what I think...
Uh..uh..
- 우발적으로 일어났다고?
- 맞아요, 그래요
- Happened?
- Yeah, yeah.
데비와 로저에 대해서는
보안관님이 옳았어요
See, you were right about Debbie
and Roger Zisk.
둘은 불륜 관계였어요
They were having an affair.
금요일 밤, 데비는 로저에게
임신했다고 말한 게 틀림없어요
On Friday night, she must've
told him she was pregnant.
아마 부인에게 말하겠다고
협박했겠죠
She probably threatened to
tell his wife.
그건 로저가 도저히
용납할 수 없는 거였죠
And that was something Roger
just couldn't... allow.
로저는 시체를 여기 가져와서
버렸습니다
He brought the body up here
to dump it.
하지만 벌에 대해 깜빡한 거죠
But he forgot about the bees.
아마 100방은 쏘였을 겁니다
They probably stung him a 100 times,
그러자 로저는 고민에 휩싸였죠
and now Roger had a problem.
언젠가는 벌 떼로 뒤덮인
데비의 시체가 발견될 텐데
Eventually somebody was
gonna find Debbie's body here
surrounded by bees
그렇게 되면, 데비가 사라진 다음 날
로저가 벌에 쏘여 나타났다는 걸
and when they did, they might remember
that Roger showed up the next day
사람들이 기억할 테니까요
covered with bee sting.
그걸 어떻게 설명하겠습니까?
How would he explain that?
로저는 다시 쏘여야만 했죠
He had to get stung again.
이번에는 벌에게 쏘인 걸
설명할 수 있도록 공공연히 말이에요
This time in public, so that
he could explain the bee stings.
도와줘요, 도와주세요
Help. Help.
살려 줘요!
누가 벌 좀 떼어 줘요!
Help. Somebody get them off me.
배짱은 있었구먼
그건 인정해야겠어
He had guts.
I'll give him that.
전부 당신 혼자 밝혀낸 겁니까?
You figured all that out?
무슨 부서에 있습니까?
What department are you with?
사실은, 전 지붕 수리공인데요
Actually, I'm a roofer.
도와 드리게 되어...
기쁩니다
I'm just glad to help..help out.
실례지만, 총은 장전하셨나요?
Excuse me.
Is your gun loaded?
- 네
- 부탁 하나만 들어주시겠어요?
- Yeah.
- Could you do me a favor?
저 좀 죽여주세요, 제발
Could you kill me, please?
왜 그냥 차 안에서 있지 않았어요?
Why didn't you just stay in the car?
차 안에 벌이 있어요
There's a bee in the car.
차 안에 벌이 있다고요
난 판사를 깨우겠소
I'm gonna wake up the judge.
그러고 나서 로저를 깨워야지
And then I'm gonna wake up Mr. Zisk.
저... 전 당신과 같이 일하죠
I... I work with you.
당신들 모두와 같이 일해요
I work with all of you.
당신은 탐정이에요
You're a detective.
자네는 샌프란시스코에서 온
훌륭한 탐정이야
You're a great detective from
San Francisco.
트루디라는 이름의 여자와
결혼했었고요 / 그래요
You were married to a woman
named Trudy. / Yes.
트루디에 대해 알아요
I know about Trudy.
- 나탈리죠
- 맞아요
- Natalie.
- That's right.
궁금한 게 수도 없으시죠
Bet you have a million questions.
맞아요, 그래요
제... 제 이름이 뭡니까?
Yes, I do.
What's... what's my name?
에이드리안
Adrian.
아뇨... 정말로 제 이름이 뭐예요?
Ha, ha, no, really, what's my name?
에이드리안
Adrian.
정말요? / 그럼
Really? / Yeah.
- 몽크 씨
- 보안관님
- Mr. Monk.
- Sheriff.
만약 일을 찾는다면
내 제안은 여전히 유효합니다
If you're looking for a job,
my offer's still good.
감사합니다
I appreciate it.
하지만 전 샌프란시스코로
돌아가야 합니다
But I have to get back
to San Francisco.
저도 나름대로의 생활이 있으니까요
I have a life.
More or less.
이방인이 되지는 말아요
Well, don't be a stranger.
내 말은, 자신에게 말이에요
I mean, to yourself.
좋은 조언이시네요
That's good advice.
보고 싶었어요
I missed you.
저도 보고 싶었어요
코라
Cora.
지붕이 다시 새요
당신은 형편없는 지붕 수리공이에요
Roof's leaking again.
You're a terrible roofer.
맞아요
That's true.
지속되리란 생각은 안 했어요
아마도 제가 밉겠죠 / 아뇨
I knew it wouldn't last.
You probably hate me. / No.
아뇨. 미워하지 않아요, 코라
고소를 하지도 않을 거고요
No, I don't hate you, Cora.
I'm not pressing charges.
그래도 좋아하지는 않잖아요
You don't like me, though.
모르겠어요. 우리 정말로
만난 적은 없죠. 그렇죠?
Well, I don't know.
We haven't really met, have we?
몽크 씨?
Monk?
이제 가야 해요
We gotta go.
자막제작 - NSC 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/tsm)